E
Enjoy the Flick ! aLDEN @ Symbianize
( TENSE MUSIC )
OFFICER : Go , go , go , go , go !
( TIRES
SCREECHING )
( SIRENS BLARING IN DISTANCE ) ( PANTING )
( TIRES
SCREECHING )
Suspect on foot , entering warehouse . In pursuit .
Go , go !
( PANTING )
Freeze ! Stop right there ! Put down the weapon !
Can 't stop it now .
Nothing can stop it . On the ground !
On the ground . Drop it , right now !
Halloran ! Detective Halloran !
( TICKING )
If he 's not here in 17 minutes , five people are gonna die .
Get Halloran here , now !
(
INDISTINCT POLICE RADIO )
MAN : Where the fuck is Halloran ?
People are gonna die , man !
Doesn 't he know ? All of you , get back .
Halloran ! Edgar !
Edgar , what the fuck are you doing ?
You put down that remote . I can 't .
What 's that for ? The games are just getting started .
What game ? His games , his rules .
I gotta choose who dies . Them or me .
Edgar , I don 't want to shoot you , but I will .
Drop the remote .
I got him , should I take it ? No , no , no . Target the remote .
If he moves to trigger it , blow it to shit .
Running out of time !
Who else is there ? Edgar ! Tell us what 's going on !
Who 's controlling you ? I 'm not fucking dying .
( ALARM SOUNDS )
( BEEPING )
(
INDISTINCT POLICE RADIO )
( GURGLES )
Which one of you assholes shot him in the chest ?
EDGAR : The game .
It 's started ...
( BUZZER BLARING )
(
PANICKED
BREATHING )
( WOMAN
WHISPERING ) What is this ?
( WOMAN GROANS )
WOMAN : What the hell ? MAN : What the fuck ?
MAN : Yo , what the hell ?
WOMAN : Oh , shit . MAN : Oh , God .
WOMAN 2 : What 's going on ?
MAN : No , no , no , no .
WOMAN : Help me !
MAN : No , no , no .
WOMAN : Help ! WOMAN 2 : Somebody please help me .
Please , help me !
Help ! Help !
WOMAN : Please , help me !
MAN : Just stay the fuck back !
(
FEEDBACK OVER
SPEAKERS )
JIGSAW : ( OVER PA ) I 'm sure you 're all wondering why you 're here .
You deny culpability , no doubt , for the circumstances
in which you find yourselves .
Salvation can be yours , if you cleanse yourselves
of the habitual lies which have brought you here .
Lies that you have told yourselves .
(
SCREAMING ) Lies that have brutalized others .
Confess . The truth will set you free .
But any attempt to violate my rules will kill you .
I want to play a game .
Fuck you !
First , an offering of blood , no matter how little ,
will give you a green light
to escape from this room with your lives .
If you can release yourself from your demons ,
you can begin to shed the chains
that those demons bring with them .
Make the simple blood sacrifice that I 've requested
or face severe consequences .
The choice is yours .
(
MACHINERY
WHIRRING )
MAN : The fuck 's going on over here ?
WOMAN 2 : No , no , no ... MAN 2 : No , no , no !
No ! ( SCREAMING )
( ALL
SCREAMING )
( SAWS
WHIRRING LOUDLY )
(
SCREAMING )
SCREAMING ) No ! No !
(
GRUNTING )
What do we do ? What do we do ?
WOMAN : Someone do something !
(
SCREAMING ,
GRUNTING )
(
GROANING )
Hey ! Wake up !
Wake up !
Stop !
" An offering of blood . "
( GRUNTS )
" No matter how little . "
" An offering of blood . "
( PANTING )
(
EXCLAIMS , PANTING )
MACHINERY
POWERING DOWN )
Cut yourself ! You need to cut yourself !
He wants blood , and then you 're free !
Cut yourself , he wants blood !
Cut yourself !
(
SCREAMING )
Fuck !
Come on , come on , come on .
(
SCREAMING )
( GASPING )
Yes ! Holy shit !
You need to cut yourself !
Get off me ! You need to cut yourself !
(
SCREAMING )
What the ...
No .
Cut yourself ! You need to cut yourself !
(
GRUNTING ) Cut yourself !
( MAN
SCREAMING )
( WOMAN SCREAMS ) ( DOORS SLAM )
(
PANICKED
BREATHING )
MAN : Where the fuck are we ?
HALLORAN : He hit the remote , but nothing triggered .
As far as we know .
MAN : You think the game 's real ?
HALLORAN : Don 't know .
MAN : Why do you think he asked for you ?
We 're good friends .
I put him away twice .
Edgar Munsen is a sociopathic meth head .
Been in and out of prison for assault and battery ,
armed robbery , drug dealing .
Nice guy .
Doc , we need him awake . We 've got questions .
Sorry , Detective .
The bullet 's lodged against the heart .
I 've got him in a barbiturate-induced coma until he stabilizes .
How long ? Swelling has to come down first .
Two hours . Two weeks . Can 't tell you .
Excuse me .
HALLORAN : Start the suspect list with Munsen 's known associates .
This is not gonna end well .
Hungry ?
(
GRUNTING )
WOMAN : Help !
( CRYING ) Please , somebody help us !
Help !
Please ! Don 't ...
Stay still .
What do you want with us ?
WOMAN : That voice ...
It said salvation can be ours if we cleanse our soul of our lies .
Is this some kind of fucked up confessional ?
The truth will set us free .
Honey , my soul is clean .
It 's Anna .
And bullshit .
I 'm Mitch .
What 's your name ?
Carly . ( GROANS )
Don 't touch me !
This is some bastard 's sick idea of a joke ?
He said it was a game .
Well , then I hope , for all of our sakes , that it is a game .
Oh , yeah ? Why is that , sweetheart ?
Because games can be won .
(
INDISTINCT CHATTER IN
DISTANCE )
( WOMAN
WHISPERING ) This is crazy .
WOMAN : What the hell ? MAN : Did anyone phone the police ?
MAN 2 : Yeah .
Underhand !
Whoa ! Overhand !
Okay , you got some heat on it !
( SIRENS
CHIRPING )
Cell phone 's off for a reason , Halloran .
Well , what do you think , El ?
( SIGHS ) I don 't know . He looks a little " pail . "
( CHUCKLES ) Let 's get this thing off .
ELEANOR : Ooh . MAN : Ah .
Hmm .
ELEANOR : Hm !
Someone 's been studying up on John Kramer .
Copycat ?
Hope not . Kramer 's been dead for ten years .
Keith ! What 's up , Doc ?
Hey , man , how you doing ? I 'm good .
Good to see you . You too , man .
You 're working this neighborhood now ? Uh , yeah , I joined homicide last month .
Jesus . What happened to this guy ?
You two know each other ?
Logan was our medic in Fallujah . Mm .
Hey , uh , I 'm sorry to hear about Christine .
How you been , man ?
Uh , good , Keith .
Yeah , I 'm doing well .
All right .
Eleanor .
KEITH : What is it ?
Okay , then .
(
MYSTERIOUS MUSIC )
LOGAN : " And then there were four ... "
You got a computer we could stick that in ?
JIGSAW 'S VOICE : ( ON LAPTOP ) The games have begun again .
And they will not stop
until the sins against the innocent are atoned for .
I will take care of the next four . You take care of the rest .
We gotta get that to voice rec .
It 's not him .
Can 't be .
Right ?
( ALL GASPING )
Aw , shit .
( METAL
CREAKING )
(
BREATHING HEAVILY )
( WHISPERING ) What the fuck ?
What the fuck ?
No , that 's not creepy at all .
(
CACKLING )
MACHINERY
RUMBLING )
No . No !
No , no , no ...
MAN : Ah , shit !
Help !
ANNA : Somebody please help us !
Where is this sick fuck taking us ?
Did anyone see anything ?
No , nothing . I got fucking drugged !
He said , " Confess " ! We have to confess !
Yeah , you got something you wanna confess ? Have at it . Come on !
(
SCREAMING )
Man , we all have something to confess !
I sold a kid a bike once .
He had an accident ten minutes after I sold it to him .
It 's not my fault he couldn 't handle such a powerful damn bike , all right ?
He died ! That 's it ?
That 's all you did ? You sold a kid a bike he died on ?
Come on , man ! That 's it ! I said that 's it , man !
Yeah , bullshit . What about you , sweetheart ? Come on !
We lost our baby .
Anna ... Anna .
Tell me that this isn 't happening .
My husband made a mistake .
MAN : No , no , no . That 's not a confession , come on , come on !
I don 't know what the fuck you want me to say , okay ?
( STAMMERS ) I let our marriage fall apart .
No , no . A confession is , " I killed a hooker in Tulsa , "
or , " I ate my fucking neighbor . " Not , " I need marriage counseling . "
MAN : Carly ? CARLY : No , nothing I can think of !
Yeah , well , think faster ! CARLY : You think faster !
( BUZZER SOUNDS ) ( ALL SCREAM )
( LOUD
CLANGING )
Oh , my God .
We 're gonna hang .
Play the damn tape , Mitch .
Oh , God !
( PANTING )
( JIGSAW ON TAPE ) While I am certain that there is a desire
to point fingers at me for the blood that has been shed ,
unless you turn that finger inward ,
I assure you , more blood will be lost
and all will be judged .
We will begin with one .
One who is not only a liar ,
but a thief . Hey !
A purse-snatcher .
And when you had a chance to fix the harm that you 'd done ,
you chose to do nothing .
Now it is you who could die without the right medication .
While unconscious , this deceiver among you ,
this criminal , was injected with a poison .
One of the syringes in front of you holds the antidote .
One is a saline solution .
The other , an acid that will cause an excruciating death .
Inject the correct one and your chains will be released .
Failure to make the right choice
could result in death for you all .
I ask you , what is a life worth to you ?
( TAPE CLICKS OFF )
One of you ' fess up , or we all die .
Okay , check yourself for marks . MAN : Huh ?
If he injected us , there could be marks .
Bingo .
What are you doing ? It 's okay . It 's okay .
You just gotta pick a needle , Blondie .
Look , we get out of these things when you pick an antidote .
Or else we all die , Carly !
No . What if it 's the acid ?
I won 't . Bullshit , you won 't .
Maybe just confess , Carly .
Okay , did you steal purses ?
Yeah , years ago , but ...
I didn 't kill anyone ! No , no , no !
No , that 's not the repentant attitude this guy 's looking for , okay ?
You 're lying ! You 're lying !
No ! I was broke , okay ?
And yes , somebody died , but it wasn 't my fault .
Okay . Choose .
Or I 'm gonna stick them all into you ! No !
Yo , man ! Are you kidding me ?
Stop ! Just let her look !
Do any of these numbers mean anything to you ?
MAN : Choose now ! I 'm trying !
( WHISPERING ) Three dollars and 53 cents .
What ? What does that mean ?
ANNA : What ? What a life is worth to me .
( PANTING )
MITCH : Oh , fuck .
Choose , right now ! Come on , pick !
Pick one ! Pick now ! Please ! I can 't do it !
MAN : Pick one now ! MITCH : We 're all going to die !
MITCH : Come on . MAN : Pick now ! Choose !
( ALL
SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY )
Come on , Carly !
I 'm not gonna fucking do it ! No , I 'm not going to !
Fuck you ! I won 't do it . MAN : Pick one , now !
Come on , pick ! Pick !
Fuck ! I 'm not gonna pick !
Come on ! Now ! Now , Carly , now !
Pick now ! ( ALL SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY )
Pick one ! ( CHOKING )
Pick one !
( ALL CHOKING )
(
GRUNTING )
( GAGGING )
(
COUGHING )
( ALL GASPING )
( ALL
COUGHING )
( GASPS )
(
GURGLING )
SCREAMING )
Fucking asshole ! Hey ! Hey !
I 'm not the one who put us here . Get a hold of yourself .
I just saved our lives .
Yeah , but you took hers . You killed her .
You selfish son of a bitch ! Stop ! Both y 'all need to chill !
What the hell ?
" A life is worth $ 3.53 . "
What ? That 's what she said .
Yeah .
(
WHISPERS ) Yeah . Three dollars and 53 cents .
MITCH : There 's more numbers on the inside of this .
It could be the combination .
Dental IDs Buckethead as Malcolm Neale .
Malcolm Neale ? I remember that case .
His wife was murdered five years ago .
A home invasion . Perp slit her throat .
He made him watch . Oh , yeah , yeah , I remember .
Malcolm Neale was a , uh , degenerate gambler .
Wife 's murder was on him . He owed some bad guys some money .
And did you ever get around to convicting those bad guys ?
ELEANOR : Scratch marks from fingernails .
There was a struggle , presumably with the killer .
The partial decapitation was made by a circular saw .
There are traces of ferric oxide , hematite , in the wound .
Rust from blades . Okay .
What about the voice recording ? Anything off the flash drive ?
The voice was John Kramer . Matched .
Identical . Matched ?
What , he came back from the dead ? Wouldn 't be his first time .
Just because someone is dead doesn 't mean they can 't have a voice .
Give us enough time , we speak for the dead .
On the roof , Edgar Munsen was spouting off about starting a game .
The recording says there are four more potential victims .
Four people fighting for their lives .
(
FLICKING LIGHT SWITCH )
( LOUD SLAM ) ( GASPS )
God ...
(
STRAINING )
Okay , we 're in the countryside somewhere .
I can 't make out any landmarks , nothing .
Oh , God . Who 's doing this to us ?
I have no idea .
What 's your name ?
Ryan .
And what 's your sin , Ryan ?
Sold bad mortgages , sold good coke ,
cheated on my taxes , cheated on my wife .
Both of them .
So , you know ...
Nothing that bad .
What 's your story , lollipop ?
It was my husband 's fault .
Oh , come on . Bullshit .
Why ... Why am I being punished for something that he did ?
Huh ?
If he hadn 't fallen asleep ,
he wouldn 't have rolled over and suffocated our baby .
( BABY
GROANING )
( CRYING ) It 's not my fault .
No , no . No !
For real , you don 't think he 's trying to tell us something ?
Look , there are two perfectly good doors right here .
Right , so we go through the door that leads exactly he wants us to go ?
No , thanks . No , Mitch is right .
I don 't think this is ... Back the fuck up .
Man , get that shit out of my face .
( BUZZER
SOUNDING ) (
GRUNTING )
( GASPING )
(
SCREAMING )
WHIMPERING )
Oh , my God !
Help me ! Help . Please . Ah ! What the fuck ?
There 's wires , there 's something ...
(
STAMMERING ,
WHIMPERING )
Help ! Help !
( RYAN
GROANING )
See ? See ?
ANNA : Looks like there 's a bunch of wires wrapped around his leg ...
and around some pulleys .
Okay , there 's , uh ... there 's some kind of handle .
Guys , there 's a tape .
( TRAP
POWERING UP )
(
SCREAMING )
It 's tighter ! It just got tighter !
Oh , God ! Okay .
Oh , God ! Oh ! Okay , how do we get the tape ?
( RYAN
WHIMPERING )
ANNA : Go slow . Oh , yeah . Be careful .
ANNA : Really slow . RYAN : Yeah , okay . Careful .
Careful . Careful . Careful .
RYAN : Oh , please be careful .
Oh , God .
(
GRUNTING )
( RYAN
WHIMPERING ) Careful , careful , careful ...
SCREAMING )
Oh , God ! Oh , God ! Oh , my God !
Oh , my ... You guys aren 't helping !
Grab the tape ! Grab the tape .
No way , man . No , you gotta fucking grab the tape .
I saved your fucking life , Mitch ! Grab the tape !
Just do it ! RYAN : Please .
RYAN : Please , yeah . Yeah , come on .
Come on . Come on , man .
Oh , my God .
You almost got it ? I 'm trying , dude !
You got it . You got it .
RYAN : Okay . All good , all good . You got it ?
Oh , God , oh , good .
You got it ? ( SOBBING )
Play the tape , Mitch . Play the tape .
No , you play the tape , man .
( JIGSAW ON TAPE ) There are no shortcuts in life .
Please forgive the rather crude example
I will make of your decision to not follow the rules .
Pull the handle and you will be set free .
What does he mean " set free " ?
Good luck , lollipop .
( SOBBING ) Oh , God .
Hey .
Prelim report on Buckethead .
It says the particles found on the body are animal feces .
Cow , chicken , pig ...
They also found traces of Aujeszky 's disease .
Aujeszky 's disease ?
It 's a virus .
Mostly known because , when swine get it ,
farmers have to wipe out the entire sounder .
I 'm impressed .
Keep digging .
( DOOR OPENS )
Maybe I can track the virus to a location .
Dr. Nelson , another one , possible jumper .
( SIRENS BLARING IN
DISTANCE )
(
INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER )
Any identification on the victim ?
No . Looks like the same killer .
This was on the body .
No link so far to any of our suspects .
Is it Kramer ? Do you know ? Is this crime related to Jigsaw ?
Think it 's any coincidence that Edgar Munsen happens to be a guest here ?
I think it 's highly unlikely he woke up from a coma ,
climbed on a roof , and threw a girl off .
But I did check with the ICU . He 's still there .
Looks like acid .
There 's a depletion of Adenosine Triphosphate
in the muscle fibers . Rigor Mortis .
Clearly , she didn 't die from the fall .
It 's hydrofluoric acid .
Look , here . This is the injection point .
The vein carried it all the way to the heart , where it 's singed .
How do you know it was hydrofluoric acid ?
Saw a lot of it in Fallujah .
Never injected , though .
A puzzle piece .
Jig-fucking-saw !
What 's Logan 's deal ? What happened in Fallujah ?
Uh , he , uh ...
He got captured . Oh .
But not before taking out three Taliban .
Well from what I heard , they tortured the shit out of him .
He spent months in the VA hospital when he got back .
Think he snapped ?
Come on , man , you 're talking about a brother .
I got a brother . He 's a fucking asshole .
What do you think about his second , Eleanor ?
She 's got a great ass , big mouth .
Seems to get off on this sick shit . Yeah .
RYAN : Motherfucker !
( SOBBING )
( PANTING )
(
STRAINING )
Shit . What the fuck ?
(
WHISPERING ) Oh , fuck .
( RYAN WHIMPERING ) I 'm a good person .
I 'm a good person , I don 't deserve this .
I confess ...
I confess . I con ...
I confess that this is fucked up !
( CRYING )
( RYAN SOBBING )
What ?
Hey , guys .
Hey , guys !
Somebody turned on the TV .
Hello ?
MITCH : Yeah , we got one , too .
I 'm gonna have to lift you . What ?
We gotta get the remote .
Okay , fine .
MITCH : Got it ?
ANNA : Got it !
(
MECHANISM
CREAKING )
( DOOR SLAMS , LATCHES )
No ! No !
No !
In the past , you have all put your own interests above others ,
and then lied to yourselves ,
and deceived the world about your callousness ,
your larceny , your criminality .
Now , you will look in the mirror
and you will face who you really are .
The choices you have made may cost you your life .
You cannot escape the truth .
There is , however , one person who can help you .
Ryan .
If he pulls the lever before you are buried alive ...
you will live .
Ryan , free yourself to free them .
Ryan .
MITCH : Ryan ?
(
MECHANISM
WHIRRING )
( BOTH PANTING )
ANNA : No ! No !
What is that ? MITCH : It 's grain !
Ryan , man , we 're gonna get buried alive ! ANNA : Ryan !
Ryan !
ANNA : Ryan !
Get to the handle ! Ryan !
I can 't ! ANNA : Ryan !
MITCH : Please , Ryan !
Hurry , man !
Ryan !
ANNA : You have to do it !
Oh , God !
ANNA : Get to the handle !
MITCH : Ryan , pull the fucking handle !
ANNA : Please !
What 's your story , sweetheart ?
What are you asking , Detective ?
You one of those , uh , kinky types ?
Like a little pain ?
Why ?
You wanna get punished ?
( LAUGHS ) Too late .
Already got an ex-wife that tortures me every day .
Maybe you deserve it . Probably .
Where were you the night Malcolm Neale got murdered ?
Home .
Alone . Cool .
Oh . Can you prove that ?
Do I need to ?
GIRL : Come home soon , Daddy . I will . I 'm ...
I 'm sorry you have to stay so late again , Judy .
Don 't worry about it .
All right , sleep sweet , Mel .
I love you .
Love you too , Daddy . Love you , bye .
Bye .
Logan .
How did you find Eleanor ?
My assistant ?
Is that all she is ?
It 's been two years since Christine passed . It 's just ...
I wouldn 't blame you . Yes , but I 'm a professional .
Uh , Logan , you ever heard of a website called " Jigsaw Rules " ?
No .
HALLORAN : Buried deep online .
Took some digging , but it 's a site devoted to Jigsaw .
Half of it 's bullshit , posers , but there 's some stuff on there ...
( CHUCKLES ) ... that is really messed up .
A lot of sick fucks .
Okay ?
We did a Darknet IP trawl . Got a lot of hits from your assistant .
She 's a regular .
Downloaded some shit you cannot imagine .
So you 're saying that Eleanor Bonneville is our copycat ?
No , that 's not what we 're saying .
You check her alibi ?
She said she was home the morning
Buckethead was found hanging in the park .
Uh , 7 : 00 A.M. ? Home alone ? Single woman ?
That does sound suspicious . All right , let 's rewind .
How did Eleanor come to you ?
She sought out the department to do her residency .
And after that ?
( CELL PHONE
VIBRATING ) After she finished her residency ?
I mean , three months ago , she was offered a job
running the show at the Cleveland city morgue .
Why didn 't she take that ?
Would you want to move to Cleveland ?
That 's the lab . Results are in .
Okay , so this is the DNA of the blood scraped from under the fingernails
of the first victim , Malcolm Neale .
KEITH : Yeah , Buckethead . Can you ID it ?
Already did .
This is a blood sample of a perp taken a decade ago .
You might remember the case .
It 's an exact match .
Whose blood is it ?
John Kramer .
What ?
( SCOFFS ) That 's impossible .
That 's a fact .
The blood under the fingernails of our first victim is John Kramer 's blood .
The Jigsaw Killer .
Ryan !
MITCH : Help !
MITCH : Ryan ! ANNA : Help !
MITCH : Pull the lever !
Ryan !
Uh ...
Uh ... ANNA : Get to the handle !
( ANNA
SCREAMING ) MITCH : Help , now !
(
GROANING )
ANNA : Ryan !
( RYAN
WHIMPERING ) ( ANNA
SCREAMING )
No !
Go to hell !
MITCH : You gotta help us now , man !
( BOTH PANTING )
Help !
( WIRES
VIBRATING )
(
WHIMPERING )
( BOTH
SCREAMING )
( GASPS ) Oh , fuck ! Oh , fuck !
(
SCREAMING )
Ryan !
MITCH : Pull the handle , Ryan ! ANNA : Ryan !
MITCH : Pull it !
Ryan !
We 're gonna die in here ! Please !
For the love of God , just pull it !
If we die , you die !
( MOANS ) Oh , God ...
(
SCREAMING ) ( PULLEYS
WHIRRING )
(
SCREAMING )
( EXHALES )
Here 's the GPS location on Ms. Bonneville 's cell .
( SIGHS ) Great .
( ALL
CLAMORING ) Is Jigsaw dead ?
Did Kramer die , or do we have proof ?
What do you have to say to all the panicked citizens who want answers ?
( ROCK MUSIC )
Turned your phone off ?
( SIGHS )
And yet here you are , you found me .
You 'd make a good detective .
Or maybe I 'm just too predictable .
Predictable ? No .
Halloran 's passing the blame around .
He 's looking at us .
Yeah . They 're watching my house .
Cause he thinks your alibi is shit .
(
CHUCKLES )
You really love that guy , huh ?
First year at County , clean case .
A predator by the name of Alistair Schultz .
Halloran roughed him up while he was in custody .
The lawyer used that to get him off .
The very next day , he kills an eight-year-old girl
who shows up on my table .
The first of many .
Halloran ...
can 't help himself .
Can 't get out of his own way .
So , no , I don 't have much love for the guy .
Well , it 's a job , Logan .
You can 't make it personal .
When you have a little girl one day ...
( SCOFFS )
Why didn 't you tell me about the job offer in Cleveland ?
You would 've told me to take it . Yes . Yes , you 're damn right I would .
It 's complicated . We are past complicated .
( SIGHS )
When Buckethead was strung up ...
I wasn 't at home like I told the cops .
I was at my , uh ...
studio . What studio ?
Why couldn 't you tell them that ?
Like I said , it 's ...
It 's complicated .
You don 't think they 're gonna find out about it ?
They know about the Jigsaw fan website , whatever the fuck you 're doing on that .
They 're gonna find out about everything .
El , they think I 'm involved .
Show me .
( SIGHS )
( DOOR CREAKS OPEN )
Oh , Jesus ! Okay ...
I should warn you , because ... Can you turn the lights on ?
( DEVICE BEEPING )
Eleanor ...
What is this ?
Hey , a girl 's gotta have a hobby .
A hobby ?
Is that what you call it ? How about a stamp collection ?
( CHUCKLES ) That 's a hobby .
( SIGHS )
(
MACHINERY
POWERING UP )
It 's beautiful , isn 't it ?
Supposedly , John Kramer designed this trap
for a game that took place before all the others .
They found the plans in his lab .
I built it myself .
Got them from some guy on the Internet .
Rumor is , not only did John design this ...
( EXHALES ) ... he built one .
Well , I 'm sorry to disappoint ,
but none of Kramer 's victims died in any device like this .
The wounds don 't match the design .
Maybe the bodies were never found .
And maybe it never happened .
Maybe someone 's playing games with you .
What are you doing with all this stuff ?
You need to get rid of it now .
(
MONITOR
BEEPING )
( RYAN
SCREAMING )
(
GROANING )
( GASPS )
(
INDISTINCT
CHATTER )
HALLORAN : Great work . Now we 've got probable cause .
You 're not gonna believe this . What ?
The commissioner wants to see Jigsaw 's remains .
Wants proof he 's really dead .
What ? Yeah .
Said he wants to calm the peoples ' fears .
Are you serious ? Chasing a dead man .
This is election year bullshit .
That is all yours . I 'm gonna follow up on these .
Right on .
(
OMINOUS MUSIC )
( PHONE
RINGING )
Halloran .
He 's in a fucking coma , how does he just disappear ?
He 's still breathing .
( MITCH
BREATHING
NERVOUSLY )
( LATCH CREAKS OPEN )
What is it ?
MITCH : It says my name .
You know what happens if we don 't follow the rules .
( GRUNTS ) (
MACHINERY
WHIRRING )
JIGSAW : Hello , Mitch .
You 've admitted to selling a boy a motorcycle .
But you have not told the entire story , have you ?
Six hundred dollars for a bike that you listed in excellent condition .
Even though you knew the brakes were faulty .
You took his 600 bucks .
And in return , you delivered him to his end .
He was my nephew , and he never hurt anyone .
The device you see here has a unique power source .
It 's the same engine that graced the bike you sold my nephew .
MITCH : Fuck . However , I assure you ,
the brake lever for this one works perfectly .
ANNA : Oh shit . Look , you 're right , man !
Avoid the dangers around you , hit the motorcycle brake handle ,
and the motor will stop . Oh , shit !
Live or die , Mitch .
The choice is yours .
(
MECHANISM
WHIRRING ) ( BIKE ENGINE STARTS )
Shit ! No , no , no !
Oh , shit .
Look , I 'm sorry ! Stop , please !
I 'm sorry about your nephew !
(
WHIRRING LOUDLY )
Anna , help !
Get the fuck up here !
I don 't want to die !
Stop ! Stop it !
Stop !
All right .
( GROANS )
(
SCREAMS )
Anna , you gotta help me !
Hurry up ! Hurry , please !
Please help ! Hurry ! Hurry !
( ANNA GRUNTS )
I don 't wanna die ! I don 't wanna die !
Mitch , pull the brake ! Pull the brake !
ANNA : Pull ... pull the brake !
(
SCREAMING )
Anna , you did it !
(
PANTING ) You saved me !
Anna ... Anna , get me out of here , please !
You did it ! Anna , you did it !
No , no , no ! ( SCREAMING )
( TRAP
POWERING DOWN )
HALLORAN : Edgar Munsen was in a coma .
You got one job !
One job to do , you useless mother ... ( CELL PHONE RINGING )
Yeah .
KEITH : Anything ?
HALLORAN : Nothing .
Pulled a Houdini . Nobody saw shit .
Just pulling Kramer 's casket out now .
HALLORAN : Reporters ?
KEITH : Yup .
Good .
End this nonsense once and for all .
John Kramer is dead and has been for ten years .
Enough of this John Kramer bullshit .
(
REPORTERS
CLAMORING )
REPORTER : It 's not him ! KEITH : Uh ...
You may wanna rethink that .
Why ? What 's going on ?
Let 's just say you can call off the hunt for Edgar Munsen .
Oh , come on !
Okay , get a warrant for Bonneville , I 'll see you there .
OFFICER : Go , go , go . OFFICER 2 : Move it ! Move it !
OFFICER 3 : Let 's go .
OFFICER 4 : Take the left . Two on the right .
(
INDISTINCT SWAT
CHATTER )
OFFICER : Go , go , go , go , go !
OFFICER 2 : Clear on the left !
OFFICER 3 : Clear !
OFFICER 2 : Watch your left .
OFFICER : Eyes up !
(
INDISTINCT SWAT
CHATTER )
(
OMINOUS MUSIC )
HALLORAN
EXHALES )
Jesus !
Two left .
So , what , Bonneville just leaves a body hanging in her studio ?
Come on , man . I know .
( SIGHS )
I 'll go pick up Logan .
I 'll get the girl .
(
KNOCKING ON DOOR )
Gonna need you to show me those wrists , brother .
I didn 't do anything , Keith . Look , listen , listen .
I have photos of you .
Yeah , you and Eleanor in your warehouse of torture devices .
Wait , you were there ? Yeah , I was there .
I just saw a third body that looks like it 's been through a meat grinder .
All right . Someone is trying to frame us .
Tell me where Eleanor is . The studio I can explain .
You just have to trust ... You know where she is ?
Keith ! I 'll tell you everything I know .
I know who did this .
And you do , too .
Who found the body at Eleanor 's studio ?
Jesus !
Halloran . He had motive .
He wanted Edgar dead .
Who ordered the targeting of the remote ?
If he moves to trigger it , blow it to shit .
Go on .
Yeah , everybody targeted the trigger ,
but did anyone actually see what Halloran was aiming at ?
He had no plan to let Edgar walk .
You think your partner knows that you 're with IA ?
( SIGHS )
So , I 'm right . Jesus .
I 've been onto Halloran since before all of this started .
IA has him connected to multiple homicides going back years .
Now these latest Jigsaw murders .
The three bodies we brought you ,
we found they 're all mixed up in Halloran 's cases .
Bring him in .
Halloran is trying to frame me .
Don 't even know what he 's got against me . ( SCOFFS ) Really ?
You know you called him out for screwing up slam-dunk cases .
You said he was a moron in the press twice .
No , I said he was an impulsive asshole ...
twice .
You blame him for what happened to Christine , don 't you ?
I don 't know how to prove Halloran 's the copycat .
It 's Halloran . It 's him .
Let me help you build your case .
Let me get you proof .
Let me open up Edgar Munsen .
We match that slug to Halloran 's gun .
(
EXHALES )
What kind of firearm do you use ? Glock 22 .
Most cops do .
Except Halloran . He 's got a 17 .
Nine by nineteen Parabellum .
That 's a Glock 17 .
( SIGHS ) Okay .
I 'll take you home . You stay there until I call you .
I 'll get Halloran .
El , where the hell are you ?
Call me , it 's urgent .
( GASPS ) Jesus !
El !
I 've been trying to call you .
I don 't know how that body ... No , no , no . It 's okay .
They don 't think it 's you or me .
They have their sights set on Halloran .
I found it .
I think I know where the game is being played .
I found the farm .
That 's great , let 's call a detective .
No !
Halloran 's behind this . We can 't trust the cops .
What ?
You wanna see this game for yourself .
You get off on this shit ?
Logan ...
This is a chance for us to save lives .
So we 're gonna take on a serial killer with what , our cunning intellects ?
And this .
RYAN : Anna ! Don 't leave me ! ( ANNA GRUNTING )
Anna ? ( ANNA STRUGGLING )
Anna ! ( ANNA SCREAMING )
I 'm bleeding out , Anna !
(
BREATHING
HEAVILY )
Motherfucker !
( GRUNTS ) ( SHOVEL
CLATTERS )
RYAN : Anna !
Okay .
Anna !
Don 't leave me , please !
(
SCREAMS )
BREATHING
HEAVILY )
(
PANTING )
( GASPS )
(
SHALLOW
BREATHING )
( ANNA
SOBBING )
(
BREATHING
HEAVILY )
Hello , Anna .
John ?
John Kramer ?
What 's going on ?
You 're about to play a game .
Oh , no , no .
What are you doing , John ? What are you doing ?
It 's a final test .
I already passed your test ! Look at my fucking leg !
That wasn 't your test , Ryan .
And that wouldn 't have been necessary ...
if you 'd simply played by the rules .
But you don 't like rules , do you ?
(
MOANING )
SOBBING )
You want me to show mercy ?
You , who hasn 't taken even a single step toward confessing ?
You , who is responsible not for one death , but for three ?
Your life of reckless deceit ...
Whoo ! Yeah ! Started in high school .
And only grew worse . Sit down !
Sit the fuck down ! Get the fuck off me !
( BOTH
SHOUTING )
( TIRES
SCREECHING )
JIGSAW : You lied to the authorities multiple times , Ryan ,
pinning the blame solely on the driver ,
your deceased best friend .
You know what you did to his family ? Hm ?
And you 've only gotten worse over the years .
I did it . Okay , I fucking did it .
I did it , but it was so long ago .
I wanna live .
I wanna live . As do I , Ryan .
As do we all .
But things happen .
Were it not for a careless mistake by a resident at the hospital I was in ...
my cancer could have been diagnosed a lot sooner .
It was simply the wrong name on an X-ray .
Would 've saved me a whole lot of hardship .
And you , Anna .
I didn 't do anything , John .
You know me !
Please don 't do this to me .
We were neighbors , Anna and I.
My first chemo sessions were very difficult , to say the least .
Anna and her husband , Matthew ,
were so kind , so supportive .
I thank you for that .
Why are you doing this to me ?
JIGSAW : Those were better days for you , weren 't they , Anna ?
But your poor husband , Matthew ...
I know the two of you didn 't always get along .
But to have to endure that tragedy , the death of a child , that 's , uh ...
one of life 's greatest burdens , isn 't it ?
If only he hadn 't fallen asleep that night .
Then he wouldn 't have rolled over and , uh , suffocated your baby .
That is what happened , right , Anna ?
( CRYING )
Shut up ! Shut up !
Shut up . Shut up !
( ANNA
SCREAMING )
(
SHALLOW
BREATHING )
I mean , it 's horrible , how horrible ,
to have to live with such a thing .
It could make a person go mad , couldn 't it ?
What are you gonna do to us ?
(
CHUCKLES ) Me ?
I 'm not gonna do anything .
You have to simply assume responsibility .
For who you are .
( TENSE ,
PULSING MUSIC )
ELEANOR : This is it .
LOGAN : How do you know this is it ?
ELEANOR : Tuck 's Pig Farm .
It was shut down due to an outbreak of Aujeszky 's disease .
Buckethead 's sample . The pig virus .
This farm was in Jill Tuck 's family .
Jigsaw 's wife .
Still is .
Although the place was shuttered years ago .
LOGAN : Well , it looks like somebody 's here .
You sure you wanna do this ?
(
OMINOUS MUSIC )
( LINE
RINGING )
( CELL PHONE
VIBRATING )
Halloran , it 's Hunt . Call me back .
( POLICE RADIO BEEPS )
We 're at Halloran 's house , but he 's not here .
You got a location on him ? Searching .
WOMAN : Sir ?
Okay , we need to bring him in . Now !
(
SHALLOW
BREATHING )
( CHAIN
RATTLING )
ELEANOR : Check this out .
That 's a lot of blood .
What 's to bet this is where Buckethead was decapitated .
It 's Jigsaw .
Jigsaw is dead .
Is he ?
( CHAINS
CLATTERING )
( GASPS )
Please ...
I 'll do anything you want , John , just please let me go .
Please .
Did you know that pigs are highly compassionate animals ?
They show distress if they see any other animal ,
including humans , suffering .
ANNA : What about you , John ?
Where is your compassion ?
We all have a thumb on the scale , Anna .
For good or for evil .
You 've been weighing in on the wrong side of the scale .
Both of you .
Now , if you want to achieve your freedom ,
you have to learn .
You have to realize that ... you 've been doing it backwards .
So ...
I 'm gonna give you an opportunity ...
to turn it all around .
( GASPS )
Here 's your key to freedom .
It 's all up to you .
Now , the game is simple .
The best ones are .
You have one shotgun .
You have one shell .
Like I said , it 's up to you .
LOGAN : How can you say Jigsaw isn 't dead ?
He 's dead .
Autopsy was performed on his body . He has his own grave .
He 's not .
Jigsaw lives forever through the work of his followers .
You .
You 've been obsessed with John Kramer from the start .
The website .
The traps you built .
Lots of people are fascinated by Kramer .
You know damn well I didn 't kill Buckethead .
Or the other two .
Then who did ?
Halloran . You said it yourself .
The bullet matches . He 's connected to all the victims .
He ... ( LOUD SMASH )
Right behind you . Drop it .
Drop it ! Both of you .
Now ! It 's him .
It 's him ! Go on !
Don 't . Don 't . Come on .
Come on ! All right !
Don 't . All right .
All right , I 'm putting it down . ( AXE CLATTERS )
Now it 's your turn , sweetheart .
Come on , sweetheart .
ELEANOR : No . Come on .
Put it down .
I 'll blow his fucking brains out .
El . Yeah .
That 's a good girl .
All right . You got what you ...
(
ELEANOR GASPS ) LOGAN : Run !
( BOTH
GRUNTING )
( METAL CLANGS )
( GROANS )
He wants us to shoot each other .
He wants me to kill you .
No .
No . No , don 't !
No , don 't touch that , you psycho bitch !
It 's the only way ! No , no !
No . No . No , okay ?
No . No , please don 't . Because that 's what he wants us to do .
Okay ? Think about it . Thumb on the scale .
No . No , please don 't . Okay ? Please .
No , no , no . Good or evil .
No , please don 't . That 's what he said .
Think about this for a minute , okay ? Just think .
We 're supposed to follow the rules . We have to play by the rules .
My only key to freedom ...
is to kill you .
( GRUNTS )
(
SHRIEKING )
WHIMPERING ) Please !
Please don 't ! Please don 't ! I 'm sorry .
I 'm sorry . Please don 't ! Please don 't !
( WHISPERS ) Backwards ...
He ... He said we 've got it backwards !
No !
(
GURGLING )
EXCLAIMS )
(
WHISPERING ) Oh , my God .
Oh , my God .
( CRYING )
(
STRAINING )
WHISPERS ) No .
No .
No !
No . No .
Here 's your key to freedom .
We could have been free , Anna .
I 'm sorry .
( GRUNTS )
(
COUGHING )
GROANING )
Halloran .
Help ! Somebody ! ( GROANING )
Help !
What the fuck are these ? What the fuck ?
These are goddamn laser cutters .
What ? What ?
Wait , wait , wait , wait , wait .
Wait , what happened ? Where 's Eleanor ?
Halloran ! Someone came out of nowhere .
Drugged me . Knocked me out .
Yeah , me too .
JIGSAW : ( ON PA ) Hello , gentlemen . You came looking for the game .
Congratulations , you found it .
You are the final two players .
It can 't be .
You may recognize the device around your collar , Dr. Nelson .
These laser cutters slice through tissue and bone like butter .
The most powerful blade on the planet .
You both have an opportunity to live .
All you need to do is confess .
Confess ? It 's that easy .
If you admit to the reason that you deserve to die ...
you can escape death .
I will be listening .
Make your choice .
How are you alive ?
How are you still alive !
The game will select one of you to begin in 60 seconds .
Unless , of course , someone chooses to go first .
Let 's neither of us touch a button .
We 're both gonna be fucked in a minute .
I 'll go first .
Okay .
( BUZZER SOUNDS ) Wait ! No , no , no , no !
No ! No ! ( GRUNTS )
Oh , God !
I 've done nothing wrong !
No ! Stop ! Stop it !
Stop it ! I 'd confess .
Yeah . Okay , okay , okay ! All right !
All right , John Kramer ! It was me !
It was me ! I fucked up !
I messed up your X-rays !
I was ... I was careless .
And I am sorry .
I 'm so sorry .
I confess .
(
SCREAMING )
Christine , I 'm so sorry , baby .
I should have been there for you .
But I wasn 't .
(
GURGLING )
SHALLOW
BREATHING ) JIGSAW : Your turn , Detective .
No ! No , no , no ! I won ! I won ! I won ! ( BUZZER SOUNDS )
(
GRUNTING )
Oh , shit !
Oh , shit . Confess .
Okay .
I did some shitty things .
But the system 's broken , I tried to fix it !
Okay ! Okay !
I tampered with evidence .
I ... I took bribes .
I put innocent people away .
Murderers and rapists walked .
People died because of me !
Innocent people died because of me !
I did it !
(
MACHINERY POWERS DOWN )
LAUGHING
NERVOUSLY )
(
EXHALES )
HALLORAN : It fucking can 't be .
What ?
Hey , hey , hey ...
( PANTING ) Wha ... What is this ?
What are you ...
HALLORAN : What ? Are you fucking kidding me ?
Logan , you ...
What ?
What ? Hey !
What ? You ...
You 're working with him ?
I am him .
What ?
And with a little help from you , no one will ever suspect it .
HALLORAN : ( ON
RECORDER ) People died because of me !
Innocent people died because of me .
I did it !
I don 't understand .
Ten years ago , in this very barn ...
a game was played .
Supposedly , John Kramer designed this
for a game that took place before all the others .
(
SCREAMING ) (
MACHINE
WHIRRING )
(
GRUNTING ) ( BLOOD
GUSHING )
(
SHOUTING ) (
GURGLING )
The bodies were never found .
LOGAN : I know this because I was one of the players .
Jigsaw put me in that game almost ten years ago .
I mixed up his X-ray .
You need to cut yourself !
( LOGAN
SCREAMS )
( GROANS )
(
PANICKED
BREATHING )
(
PANTING )
John decided I shouldn 't have to die over an honest mistake .
He gave me a second chance .
So now , ten years later ,
I 've recreated Jigsaw 's game with criminals from your failed cases .
What ?
LOGAN : I wanted my game to be identical to Jigsaw 's .
So I went through your cases .
Found players just like the ones in the original game .
I gave them the same choices that Jigsaw did a decade ago .
Jigsaw put five people in his game .
I put in three .
You and I are the last two .
I wanted to see if I was as worthy as him .
As ... talented .
No ...
Come on , Logan .
Come on . Have mercy .
Like you just had mercy on me ?
When you started our game just now ?
Pushing my button ?
Saving yourself .
What ?
That 's not fair !
Fair ?
Why was Edgar Munsen free ?
He was a murderer .
But you were protecting him because he was your criminal informant years ago .
And you let him walk free .
Edgar Munsen killed my wife .
You don 't ... You don 't know that . It 's never been proven .
(
PANTING )
This ...
won 't ...
bring your family back .
John Kramer ...
gave people a chance to win the game .
A choice .
Fuck ! You fucker .
You have a choice .
Scream , or don 't .
Logan , Logan , Logan , Logan . Hey , look , I can help you .
I can ... I can do things for you .
Can you bring my wife back ?
Doesn 't matter what I say , does it ?
LOGAN : I created a game that appeared to be run by Jigsaw .
(
CLICKING MOUSE )
( DEVICE BEEPS )
JIGSAW 'S VOICE : Hello , Edgar . You 're about to play a game .
Five lives are in your hands .
Follow my instructions exactly .
( TAPS
KEYBOARD )
I gotta choose who dies , them or me .
I 'm not fucking dying .
What kind of firearm do you use ?
KEITH : Glock 22 . Most cops do .
Except Halloran , he 's got a 17 .
Nine by nineteen Parabellum . That 's a Glock 17 .
The blood under the fingernails of our first victim ...
is John Kramer 's blood .
LOGAN : Some will think it 's Jigsaw .
Some will suspect you .
But no one will suspect me .
Okay , we need to bring him in . Now !
LOGAN : Because Eleanor will provide my alibi .
ELEANOR : Oh , yes .
Ten years ago , I came out of the war a broken man .
Jigsaw put the pieces of my life back together again .
He gave my life purpose .
(
SOBBING )
We can never come from anger or from vengeance .
You taught me that .
But then there will be no justice .
Ah , but there will !
Because we 'll speak for the dead .
LOGAN : Together , we built a legacy .
( THUD
ECHOING )
Now , I speak for the lives ruined by people like you .
Murderers . Rapists .
Their victims appeared on my table because of you .
No . No .
No ...
( GROANS )
(
CLIMACTIC MUSIC RISES )
I speak for the dead .
aLDEN @ Symbianize
(
OMINOUS MUSIC )
( ROCK MUSIC )
(
OMINOUS MUSIC )
( MUSIC FADES )